(弗吉尼亚州匡蒂科附近森林)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(BIRDS CALLING)
朱迪·福斯特(克拉丽丝·斯塔琳)
安东尼·霍普金斯(莱克特·汉尼拔)
斯科特·格林(杰克·克劳弗尔)
沉默的羔羊
泰德·拉文(詹姆·甘姆-野牛比尔)
安东尼·希尔德(基顿医生)
(PANTING)
MAN: Starling!
斯达琳！
Starling!
Crawford wants to see you in his office.
克劳福德要见你
Thank you, sir.
谢谢
(伤害)
(苦难)
(痛苦)
(喜欢它)
- Clarice.
- Hey.
- 克拉丽丝
- 你好
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(行为科学组)
...so there shouldn't be any problem if you could...
……应该不会有任何问题，只要你能……
- You looking for Crawford?
- Yes, sir.
找克劳福德吗？
He should be back in a couple minutes.
他应该很快就回来了
Why don't you wait in his office?
在他的办公室等一会吧
Okay.
好的
And I think they were over in flushing...
再说我觉得他们太过于……
(比尔剥下第五个人的皮)
Starling,
斯达琳
Clarice M. Good morning.
早安，克拉丽丝
Good morning, Mr. Crawford.
早安，克劳福德先生
Sorry to pull you off of the course at such short notice.
抱歉突然把你召离课堂
Your instructors tell me you're doing well.
你的导师说你很不错
Top quarter of your ciass.
是班里的高材生
I hope so. They haven't posted any grades yet.
希望是吧，他们还没有公布成绩
A job's come up, and I thought about you.
有一个任务要办，于是我想起你
Not a job, really.
这不是正式的任务
More of an interesting errand.
更像一份有趣的差事
Sit down.
坐下
Yes, sir.
是，长官
I remember you from my seminar at UVA.
我记得你上过我在弗吉尼亚大学的研讨班
You grilled me pretty hard, as I recall,
我记得，你追问我很紧……
on the Bureau's civil rights record in the Hoover years.
问我本局在胡佛年代的公民权利记录
I gave you an "A."
我给了你“甲等”
A-minus, sir.
是甲下
Let's see. Double major, psych and criminology. Graduated magna.
双主修，心理学及犯罪学，以优异成绩毕业
Summer internships at the Reitzinger CIinic.
在瑞辛格疗养院做过夏季实习
It says here when you graduate,
它说你毕业后……
you want to come to work for me in Behavioral SClence.
想在行为科学组替我工作
Yes, very much, sir. Very much.
是的，我很想
We're interviewing all the serial killers now in custody...
我们正在访问被囚禁的连环杀手……
for a psycho-behavioral profile.
进行变态行为的分析
It could be a real help in unsolved cases.
对一些悬案会有很大帮助
Most of them have been happy to talk to us.
他们大都乐意跟我们谈
Do you spook easily, Starling?
你会否很容易受惊？
Not yet, sir.
不会
See, the one we want most, refuses to cooperate.
我们最想见的那个人拒绝合作
I want you to go after him again today in the asylum.
我想你去精神病院找他
And who's the subject?
那个人是谁？
The psychiatrist Hannibal Lecter.
心理医生汉尼拔·莱克特
Hannibal the Cannibal.
食人狂魔汉尼拔
I don't expect him to talk to you,
我想他不会跟你交谈
but I have to be able to say we tried.
但无论怎么样我们都得尝试
So if he won't cooperate,
如果他不合作……
I want just straight reporting.
我希望你如实报告
How's he look? How's his cell look?
他的容貌和监狱里的状况怎么样？
Is he sketching, drawing?
他有没有素描、绘画？
If he is, what's he sketching?
如果有，他都画些什么？
Here's a dossier on Lecter.
这是莱克特的档案……
A copy of our questionnaire and a special ID for you.
问卷副本和你的特别身份证
Have your memo on my desk by 0800 Wednesday.
周三早上八点把你的报告交给我
Okay.
好的
Excuse me, sir, but why the urgency?
对不起，长官，为什么这样急？
Lecter's been in prison for so many years now.
莱克特已经坐牢很多年了
Is there some connection between him and Buffalo Bill maybe?
他和水牛比尔是否有关联？
I wish there were.
但愿有
I want your full attention, Starling.
我要你非常留意，斯达琳
Yes, sir.
是的，长官
Be very careful with Hannibal Lecter.
要非常小心应付汉尼拔·莱克特
Dr. Chilton at the asylum will go over...
精神病院的奇尔顿医生会……
all the physical procedures used with him.
给你讲解接见程序
Do not deviate from them for any reason whatsoever,
无论如何不能偏离程序……
and you're to tell him nothing personal, Starling.
你绝对不能向他透露私人事情，斯达琳
Believe me, you don't want Hannibal Lecter inside your head.
相信我，你不会希望汉尼拔·莱克特知道你在想什么
Just do your job, but never forget what he is.
执行你的任务，但千万别忘记他是什么
And what is that?
是什么？
CHILTON: Oh, he's a monster.
哦，他是个魔头
A pure psychopath.
一个变态狂人
So rare to capture one alive.
可以生擒一个已很难得了
From a research point of view,
从研究角度来说……
Lecter is our most prized asset.
莱克特是我们最有价值的资产
Well.
那好
You know, we get a lot of detectives here,
你知道，我们这儿以前来过很多探员
but I must say, I can't ever remember one as attractive.
但我得说，不记得有过这么有魅力的
Will you be in Baltimore overnight?
你会在巴尔的摩过夜吗？
Because this can be quite a fun town if you have the right guide.
因为如果你有适当的向导，这可以是个很好玩的城市
Well, I'm sure this is a great town, Dr. Chilton,
我肯定这是个了不起的城市
but, uh, my instructions are to talk to Dr. Lecter...
但给我的指示是要同莱克特医生交谈……
and report back this afternoon.
然后下午回去报告
I see.
我明白了
Let's make this quick, then.
那么我们快点吧
We've tried to study him, of course,
当然，我们尝试过研究他……
but he's much too sophisticated for the standard tests.
但他太高深了，一般的测试都不适用
Oh, my, does he hate us!
哦，天啊，他多么讨厌我们啊！
He thinks I'm his nemesis.
他觉得我是他的报应
Crawford's very clever, isn't he? Using you.
克劳福德真是聪明，对吧？利用你
CLARICE: What do you mean, sir?
你什么意思，先生？
A pretty young woman to turn him on.
找个漂亮的女郎来引诱他
I don't believe Lecter's even seen a woman in eight years.
我相信这八年来莱克特都没见过女人
And, oh, are you ever his taste.
而你正合他的胃口
So to speak.
恕我直言
I graduated from UVA, Doctor.
我毕业于弗吉尼亚大学，医生
It is not a charm school.
它不是一间仪态学校
Good. Then you should be able to remember the rules.
很好，你该能记着那些规矩了
(MAN SHOUTING)
Do not touch the glass.
不要触摸那块玻璃
Do not approach the glass.
也不要接近那块玻璃
You pass him nothing but soft paper.
只可传递柔软的纸张给他
No pencils or pens.
不能传铅笔或钢笔
No staples or paper clips on his paper.
纸张上不能有钉书钉或夹子
Use the sliding food carrier. No exceptions.
只可用那个活动食物架传送，不得有例外
If he attempts to pass you anything, do not accept it.
如果他想给你传东西，不得接受
Do you understand me?
明白吗？
Yes, I understand, sir.
是的，明白，先生
(BUZZER BUZZING)
I'm going to show you why we insist on such precautions.
我让你看看，为什么我们坚持如此戒备
On the afternoon of July 8, 1981,
在1981年7月8日的下午……
he complained of chest pains...
他说胸口痛……
and was taken to the dispensary.
被带往医疗室
His mouthpiece and restraints were removed for an EKG.
为方便做心电图，他的口罩被除下
When the nurse leaned over him, he did this to her.
当护士靠近他身边时，他对她做了这个
The doctors managed to reset her jaw, more or less,
医生们多少算是重整了她的下颚……
save one of her eyes.
救回她一只眼睛
His pulse never got above 85,
即使在他吃她的舌头时……
even when he ate her tongue.
他的脉搏从没超过85
I keep him in here.
我把他关在这里
Dr. Chilton.
奇尔顿医生
If Lecter feels that you're his enemy,
如果莱克特觉得你是他的敌人……
then, uh, well, maybe we'll have more luck...
那么，嗯，如果我单独去的话……
if I go in by myself.
我们运气可能会好一点
What do you think?
你认为怎么样？
(BEEPING)
You might have suggested this in my office...
你如果在我办公室时提出来……
and saved me the time.
就可以省掉我的时间了
Yes, sir, but then I... I would have missed...
是的，但我……我会错过了……
the pleasure of your company, sir.
与你同行的乐趣
When she's finished, bring her out.
她完事后带她出去吧
Hi. I'm Barney.
你好，我是巴尼
He told you, don't get near the glass?
他告诉过你，不要靠近那块玻璃吧？
Yes, he did. Clarice Starling.
对，他说过了，我是克拉丽丝·斯达琳
Mmm-hmm. Nice to meet you, Clarice.
嗯。幸会，克拉丽丝
You can hang your coat up here if you like.
你可以把大衣挂在那里
Thank you. I will.
好的，谢谢你
He's past the others. The last cell.
他在最尽头的那个牢房
You keep to the right.
靠右走吧
I put out a chair for you.
我给你放了一张椅子
Oh, yes. That's very good. Thank you.
哦，好的，太好了，谢谢你
I'll be watching. You'll do fine.
我会看着，你不会有事的
INMATE: Hi.
嗨
I can smell your cunt.
我可以闻到你的私处
Good morning.
早安
Dr. Lecter, my name is Clarice Starling.
莱克特医生，我叫克拉丽丝·斯达琳
May I speak with you?
可以和你谈谈吗？
You're one of Jack Crawford's, aren't you?
你是杰克·克劳福德的人，是吗？
I am, yes, sir.
是的，我是，先生
May I see your credentials?
我可以看看你的证件吗？
Certainly.
当然可以
Closer, please.
靠近一点，劳烦你
Closer.
近一点
That expires in one week.
一周内后就到期了
You're not real FBI, are you?
你不是真正的联邦调查局探员，是吧？
I'm still in training at the Academy.
我还在学院里受训
Jack Crawford sent a trainee to me?
克劳福德派个见习生来见我？
Yes. I'm a student.
是的，我是个学生
I'm here to learn from you.
我是来向你学习的
Maybe you can decide for yourself...
也许你可以自己决定……
whether or not I'm qualified enough to do that.
我是不是够资格这样做
Mmm.
嗯
That is rather slippery of you, Agent Starling.
你这人非常狡猾呢，斯达琳探员
Sit, please.
请坐吧
Now, then. Tell me,
那么，现在告诉我……
what did Miggs say to you?
米格斯对你说了什么？
Multiple Miggs in the next cell.
隔壁的『多面人米格斯』
He hissed at you.
他向你发出嘶嘶声
What did he say?
他说了些什么？
He said, "I can smell your cunt."
他说『我可以闻到你的私处』
I see.
是吧
I myself cannot.
我可闻不到
(INHALING)
You use Evyan skin cream.
你用爱肤恩润肤膏
And sometimes you wear L'Air du Temps,
有时你会用点L'Air du Temps香水……
but not today.
但今天没有
Did you do all these drawings, Doctor?
这些画是你画的吗，医生？
Ah!
啊！
That is the Duomo, seen from the Belvedere.
那是从观景楼远望的佛罗伦萨大教堂
You know Florence?
你知道佛罗伦斯吗？
All that detail just from memory, sir?
那些细节都是来自记忆的吗？
Memory, Agent Starling, is what I have instead of a view.
斯达琳探员，我只有记忆，没有景观
Well,
那么……
perhaps you'd care to lend us your view on this questionnaire, sir.
或许你可以在这份问卷上给我们一些见解，先生
Oh, no, no, no, no.
哦，不，不，不，不
You were doing fine.
你做得很不错
You had been courteous and receptive to courtesy.
你很有礼，而且能接受礼貌
You had established trust with the embarrassing truth about Miggs.
你很坦率告诉我米格斯的下流话，来取得我的信任
And now this ham-handed segue into your questionnaire.
现在却又拿出了这份拙劣的问卷
(CLICKING TONGUE)
It won't do.
这可不行
I'm only asking you to look at this, Doctor.
我只是要求你看看它，医生
Either you will or you won't.
做不做随便你
Yeah.
对
Jack Crawford must be very busy indeed,
克劳福德一定是忙得不可开交……
if he is recruiting help from the student body.
否则他不会从学校找个女学生来帮忙
Busy hunting that new one, Buffalo Bill.
忙于追捕那个新人，水牛比尔吧
What a naughty boy he is.
他可真是个淘气的坏孩子
Do you know why he's called Buffalo Bill?
你可知道为什么他被称为水牛比尔？
Please tell me. The newspapers won't say.
请告诉我。报纸上可不会说
Well, it started as a bad joke in Kansas City Homicide.
是来自堪萨斯城凶案组的一个笑话
They said, "This one likes to skin his humps."
他们说，『这个人喜欢剥他猎物的皮』
Why do you think he removes their skins,
你认为他为什么要剥她们的皮……
Agent Starling?
斯达琳探员？
Enthrall me with your acumen.
用你的敏锐来振奋我一下吧
It excites him.
这样做令他兴奋
Most serial killers keep some sort of trophies from their victims.
大部分的连环杀手都会保存受害人身上的东西作为纪念品
I didn't.
我可没有
No.
对
No, you ate yours.
你吃了他们
You send that through now.
把那个传过来吧
Hmm.
嗯
Oh, Agent Starling,
哦，斯达琳探员
you think you can dissect me with this blunt, little tool?
你觉得凭这份拙劣的东西就可以分析我？
No!
不是！
I... I thought that your knowledge...
我……我相信你的学识……
You're so ambitious, aren't you?
你很有野心，是不是？
You know what you look like to me...
你知道你拿着那个高级皮包……
with your good bag and your cheap shoes?
和穿着廉价鞋子对我来说像个什么？
You look like a rube.
像个土包子
A well-scrubbed, hustling rube with a little taste.
一个干净、忙碌，带点品味的土包子
Good nutrition has given you some length of bone,
足够的营养给了你体骼的成长……
but you're not more than one generation from poor white trash,
但也只是从你这代起才跳出了白人下层阶层……
are you, Agent Starling?
是不是，斯达琳探员？
And that accent you've tried so desperately to shed,
你极力想摆脱那不由自主流露出的口音……
pure West Virginia.
地道的西弗吉尼亚腔调
(IN SOUTHERN ACCENT) What does your father do?
你父亲是做什么的？
Is he a coal miner?
他是个矿工吗？
Does he stink of the lamp?
他不是满身带着矿灯的臭气？
And, oh, how quickly the boys found you.
还有，哦，那些男孩多迅速就搭上了你
All those tedious, sticky fumblings in the back seats of cars,
在单调沉闷、闷热肮脏的汽车后座里胡乱摸你……
while you could only dream of getting out, getting anywhere,
而你却梦想着走出去，去任何地方……
getting all the way to the FBI.
一直走到联邦调查局
You see a lot, Doctor.
你很有观察力，医生
But are you strong enough to point...
但你是否强大到能……
that high-powered perception at yourself?
用这敏锐的观察力来分析你自己？
What about it? Why don't you...
怎么样？为什么你……
Why don't you look at yourself and write down what you see?
为什么你不探究一下自己，把观察所得写下来？
Maybe you're afraid to.
或者你害怕这样做吧
(THUDDING)
A census-taker once tried to test me.
曾经有一个人口调查员想测试我
I ate his liver with some fava beans,
我把他的肝配着蚕豆吃了……
and a nice Chianti.
还有上好的基安蒂干红呢
(HISSING)
You fly back to school now, little Starling.
小斯达琳，你飞回学校去吧
Fly, fly, fly.
飞吧，飞吧，飞吧
(MIGGS MOANING)
MIGGS: I bit my wrist so I could die.
我咬我的手腕，那样我就可以死了
Look at the blood!
看这些血！
Gotcha!
你上当了！
Miggs! You stupid fuck!
米格斯！你这愚蠢的混蛋！
Hannibal the Cannibal!
食人狂魔汉尼拔！
Agent Starling! Come back!
斯达琳探员！回来！
Agent Starling! Agent Starling!
斯达琳探员！斯达琳探员！
I would not have had that happen to you.
我不会让那种事情再发生在你身上的
Discourtesy is unspeakably ugly to me.
不礼貌的对我来说就是难言的丑陋
Then do this test for me.
那么帮我做这个测验吧
No, but I will make you happy.
不做，但我会令你开心的
I'll give you a chance for what you love most.
我会给你一个你最喜欢的大好机会
And what is that, Doctor?
是什么，医生？
Advancement, of course. Now listen carefully.
当然是升职。现在仔细听着
Look deep within yourself, Clarice Starling.
你自我反省一下，克拉丽丝·斯达琳
Go seek out Miss Mofet, an old patient of mine.
去找出莫菲特小姐，我从前的一个病人
- M-o-f-e-t. Go now.
- Doctor.
- M-O-F-E-T。现在去吧
- 医生
I don't think Miggs could manage again quite so soon,
我相信米格斯不会这么快发作的……
even though he is crazy.
虽然他是疯的
Go now!
快去！
(INMATES SCREAMING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Hey, Bill.
你好，比尔
Hey.
嘿
Daddy!
爸爸！
Hey, Clarice.
嘿，克拉丽丝
How are you?
你好吗？
Did you get any bad guys today, Daddy?
爸爸，你有没有抓到坏人？
No, angel, they all got away.
没有，小天使，他们跑掉了
Aw, shoot.
啊，真糟
(DOG BARKING)
(CLARICE SOBBING)
FBI! Hands up! Don't move!
联邦调查局，举手，别动！
Turn around!
转过身来！
Hands behind your back! Thumbs up.
把双手放在后面！好的
(SIREN WAILING)
You're dead, Starling.
斯达琳，你已经死了
Johnson, good job. Good entry. Good commands.
约翰逊，进入和指挥都做得很好
- Starling, where's your danger area?
- In the corner, sir.
- 斯达琳，你哪里有危险？
- 在角落
- Did you check the corner?
- No, sir.
- 你有没有检查过它？
- 没有，长官
That's the reason you're dead.
所以你已经死了
3-1-0-9?
是3109？
Breaking doors or windows to enter or exit.
打破门或窗闯入或者撤退
Rule 404...
404号规则呢？
(巴尔的摩心理医生，获得最高荣誉)
(著名心理医生被控谋杀)
(PHONE RINGING)
(食人狂魔审讯带来新的恐怖)
Clarice, phone.
克拉丽丝，你的电话
- It's the guru.
- Crawford?
- 是教官
- 克劳福德？
Yeah. Thanks, Ardelia.
是的，谢谢，阿德利亚
Starling?
斯达琳？
CLARICE: Sir?
长官？
Miggs is dead.
米格斯死了
Dead? How?
死了？怎么会？
The orderly heard Lecter whispering to him all afternoon,
守卫听到汉尼拔·莱克特整个下午对他低声说话……
and Miggs crying.
而米格斯在大叫
They found him at bed check.
他们在夜间巡查时发现了他
He'd swallowed his own tongue.
他吞掉了自己的舌头
Starling?
斯达琳？
Yeah, I'm... I'm still here, sir.
是的，我……我还在听，长官
I just... I don't know how to feel about this.
我只是……我不知道对这件事该有什么感想
You don't have to feel any way about it.
你没必要感想什么
Lecter did it to amuse himself.
莱克特这样做只是为了自娱
Look, I know it got ugly today,
我明白今天很难受……
but you mentioned a name at the end. Mofet.
但你最后提到了一个莫菲特的名字
Any follow-up on her?
有后续行动吗？
Uh, well, Lecter altered or destroyed...
莱克特在被捕前……
most of his patients' histories prior to capture,
把大部分病人的病历销毁了……
so there's no record of anyone named Mofet.
所以没有任何名叫莫菲特的人的记录
But, uh, I thought the "yourself" reference...
但……嗯……我觉得他用了『你自己』这个词……
was, uh, too hokey for Lecter,
这对莱克特来说太做作了……
so I figured, he's from Baltimore,
所以我想，他来自巴尔的摩……
and I looked in the phone book,
于是就翻查电话簿……
and there's a "Your Self Storage" facility,
那里有一间叫『你自己』的自助式仓库……
right outside of downtown Baltimore, sir.
就在巴尔的摩市外围，长官
Unit 31 was leased for 10 years,
31号仓已经租了十年……
prepaid in full.
租金是全数预缴的
The contract
合约……
is in the name of a Miss Hester Mofet.
是签在海斯特·莫菲特小姐的名下的
So nobody's been in here since 1980?
自从1980年就没有人来过了？
Not to my knowledge.
据我所知是没有
Privacy is a great concern to my customers.
我的顾客都很重视隐私权的
(GRUNTING) Yes, I won't disturb anything. I promise.
好的，我保证不会扰乱任何东西
I'll be out of here before you know it.
我很快就会离开
- May I help you?
- Yes, actually, you can.
- 我能帮忙吗？
- 是的，你可以
(DOOR BANGING)
It's stuck.
它被卡着了
We could return tomorrow with my son.
我们可以等于明天跟我的儿子一起来
What about him?
他怎么样？
I would ask my driver to help you,
我本可叫我的司机帮你……
but he detests physical labor.
但他讨厌体力劳动
Great.
太好了
You just stay here. I'll be back in one minute.
你别走开，我很快回来
(METALLIC CLANKING)
(GRUNTING)
It's stuck.
它被卡着了
Hand me that flashlight, sir.
先生，请把那支电筒递给我
(METALLIC CLATTERING)
Oh.
哦
Um...
嗯……
If this door should fall down...
如果这道门跌下来……
(CHUCKLES) or anything else, uh,
或者有什么意外，呃……
this is the number for our Baltimore field office.
这是我们巴尔的摩地方办公室的电话号码
Now, they know that you're with me.
他们知道你跟我在一起的
You call them if anything should happen.
如果有意外你就给他们打电话吧
Yes, Miss Starling.
好的，斯达琳小姐
(TROUSER FABRIC RIPPING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(THUNDER CRACKING)
(THUDDING)
Clarice. Here. They're waiting for you. Watch your step.
克拉丽丝，这边。他们在等你，小心你的脚下
Thank you.
谢谢
CLARICE: Hester Mofet.
『海斯特·莫菲特』
It's an anagram, isn't it, Doctor?
是拼字猜谜，对吧，医生？
Hester Mofet, "The rest of me."
意思是『我其余的东西』
"Miss The Rest Of Me," meaning that you rented that garage?
『我其余的东西』，那表示车库是你租的？
Thank you.
谢谢
Your bleeding has stopped.
你的血已经止住了
How did you...
你怎么……？
It's nothing.
没什么的
It's just a scratch.
只是擦伤而已
Dr. Lecter, whose head is in that bottle?
莱克特医生，那瓶里的头颅是谁的？
Why don't you ask me about Buffalo Bill?
你为什么不问我关于水牛比尔的事？
Why, do you know something about him?
你知道他的什么事吗？
I might, if I saw the case file.
有可能，如果我看过他的档案
You could get that for me.
你可以替我拿他的档案
Why don't we talk about Miss Mofet?
我们为什么不谈谈莫菲特小姐呢？
You wanted me to find him.
你要我去找他
His real name is Benjamin Raspail.
他的真名是本杰明·拉斯佩尔
A former patient of mine,
我的一个前病患……
whose romantic attachments ran to, shall we say, the exotic.
他的恋爱对象，有点怪异
I did not kill him, I assure you.
我没有杀他，我向你保证
Merely tucked him away very much as I found him,
只是把他藏起来，就像我发现他时的样子……
after he'd missed three appointments.
在他错过了三次预约之后
If you didn't kill him, then who did, sir?
如果你没有杀他，那么是谁杀的，先生？
Who can say?
谁知道呢？
Best thing for him, really.
这对他来说是最好的结果了
His therapy was going nowhere.
他的治疗完全没有效果
His dress, uh, makeup...
他的裙子、化妆……
Raspail was a transvestite?
拉斯佩尔是个异性装扮癖好者？
In life? Oh, no.
生活中？哦，不是
Garden variety manic-depressive.
不是，只是普通的躁狂抑郁
Tedious. Very tedious.
乏味，非常乏味
And I just think of him as a kind of experiment,
现在我把他看成是一个实验……
a fledgling killer's first effort at transformation.
一个初出茅庐的杀手的第一次转变的努力
How did you feel when you saw him, Clarice?
你看到他时有什么感觉？
Scared at first, then,
最初吓坏了，后来……
exhilarated.
就很振奋
Jack Crawford is helping your career, isn't he?
克劳福德在提携你的职业生涯，是吗？
Apparently, he likes you, and you like him, too.
看来你们互相倾慕呢
I never thought about it.
我从没有想过
Do you think Jack Crawford wants you sexually?
你认为克劳福德对你有性方面的欲望吗？
True, he is much older,
真的，他年纪大了很多……
but do you think he visualizes scenarios, exchanges,
但你觉得他对你有过想入非非吗？交换……
fucking you?
操你？
That doesn't interest me, Doctor.
这吸引不了我，医生
Frankly, it's... It's the sort of thing that Miggs would say.
坦白说，这是……这是米格斯会说的那种话
Not anymore.
他不会再说了
Thank you, Barney.
谢谢你，巴尼
(INDISTINCT)
CLARICE: What happened to your drawings?
你的那些画呢？
Punishment, you see, for Miggs.
惩罚，你知道的，为了米格斯那件事
Just like that gospel program.
就像那个福音传播节目……
When you leave, they'll turn the volume way up.
你离开后他们就会调高声音
Dr. Chilton does enjoy his petty torments.
奇尔顿医生喜欢这些折磨伎俩
What did you mean by transformation, Doctor?
你说转变是什么意思？
I've been in this room for eight years now, Clarice.
克拉丽丝，我在这里已经八年了
I know they will never, ever let me out while I'm alive.
我知道在我有生之年，他们都不会释放我
What I want is a view.
我想要的是一个景观
I want a window where I can see a tree, or even water.
我想要一个能看到树和水的窗户
I want to be in a federal institution far away from Dr. Chilton.
我想去一间远离奇尔顿医生的联邦监狱
What did you mean by fledgling killer?
你说『初出茅庐的杀手』是什么意思？
Are you saying that he's killed again?
你是否说他已经再次杀人？
I'm offering you a psychological profile on Buffalo Bill,
我根据案件的证据，给你对水牛比尔……
based on the case evidence.
进行心理分析
I'll help you catch him, Clarice.
我会帮你抓住他，克拉丽丝
You know who he is, don't you?
你知道他是谁，是不是？
Tell me who decapitated your patient, Doctor.
告诉我，谁把你的病人斩首了，医生
All good things to those who wait.
愿意等待的人才有好结果
I've waited, Clarice,
我已经等了……
but how long can you and old Jackie boy wait?
但你和老杰克能等多久？
Our little Billy must already be searching...
我们的小比尔一定正在找寻着……
for that next special lady.
下一位特别的女士了
∮ After all it was a great big world ∮
(田纳西州孟斐斯市)
∮ With lots of places to run to ∮
(SINGING) ∮ Yeah, and if she had to die ∮
∮ Trying she ∮
∮ Had one little promise she was gonna keep ∮
∮ Oh, yes ∮
∮ All right ∮
∮ Take it easy, baby ∮
∮ Make it last all night ∮
∮ She was an American girl ∮
(BEEPING)
(CAT MEOWING)
Hey, little cheeper.
小猫咪
I'll be right there.
我就快上来了
MAN: Oh, shoot.
哦，糟糕
Goddamn it.
该死
Perfect! Jesus.
太好了！天啊！
Can I help you with that?
要我帮忙吗？
Would you?
可以吗？
Sure.
当然可以
- Thank you.
- That's all right.
- 谢谢你
- 不用客气
You look kind of handicapped.
你好像是伤残人士
Yeah.
是的
I got it this far.
我搬了很远了
I just can't get it up in the truck.
但我就是搬不上货车
Here. Just grab this.
来吧，抓着，上！
Okay.
好的
Good. Just set it down. That's good.
好，把它放下吧，很好
Uh, get in the truck.
你上车
I want to push it all the way up.
我想把它推进去
I really appreciate this. Thank you. All right.
真的很谢谢你
Yeah.
好的
Thank you.
谢谢
Just go all the way back.
进到后面去
Okay. Is this good?
好了，行了吗？
Yeah, that's good.
行了，很好
That's great.
真好
Okay.
好的
Say, are you about a size 14?
你大概穿十四号吧？
Sorry?
什么？
(GIRL GROANING)
(十四号)
MAN: Good.
好
(GIRL WHIMPERING)
Oh, good. Good.
哦，好啊，好啊
MAN: Hold!
抓着！
(GRUNTING)
一！
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
Starling!
斯达琳！
Outside. Let's go.
出去，我们走吧
Cindy, in the ring for Starling. Let's go!
辛蒂，进场代替斯达琳。我们走吧！
(SIRENS BLARING)
FBI! Hold it! Hold it right there!
FBI！站住！站住不许动！
Saddle up. Pack your field gear. You're moving out.
打包，收拾你的装备，你要出发了
- You're going with Crawford.
- Where?
- 你会跟克劳福德一起去
- 去哪里？
Found a girl's body down in West Virginia.
在西弗吉尼亚南部发现了一名女子尸体
Been in the water about a week.
她在水里一周了
Looks like a Buffalo Bill-type situation.
看来是水牛比尔干的
(AIRPLANE ENGINE WHIRRING)
(西弗吉尼亚州克莱县)
(联邦调查局)
CRAWFORD: He keeps them alive for three days.
他让她们活了三天
We don't know why.
我们不知道原因
There's no evidence of rape or physical abuse prior to death.
死前没有强奸或虐待的迹象
All the mutilation you see there is postmortem.
这些伤口都是死后造成的
Okay, three days.
三天……
Then he shoots them, skins them, and dumps them.
然后他开枪射死她们，剥皮和弃尸
Each body in a different river.
每个尸体弃置在不同的河里
The water leaves us no trace evidence of any kind.
河水冲走了证据
That's Fredrica Bimmel, the first one.
那是第一个，弗瑞德瑞卡·比默尔
Her body was the only one he took the trouble to weight down,
她的尸体是唯一被他费力沉下去的……
so actually, she was the third girl found.
实际上，她是第三个被发现的
After her, he got lazy.
继她之后，他变得懒惰了
Okay. Let's see.
好的，我们看看
Circles where the girls were abducted,
圆圈是那些女子被掳走的位置……
arrows where their bodies were found.
箭嘴是尸体被发现的地点
This new one today washed up here.
今天这个被冲到这里来
Elk River, West Virginia.
在西弗吉尼亚州埃尔克河被发现
Look at him, Starling. Tell me what you see.
斯达琳，仔细看看，告诉我你有什么发现
Well, he's a white male.
他是个白种男人
Serial killers tend to hunt...
连环杀手，倾向于……
within their own ethnic groups.
在自己的族群中猎杀
He's not a drifter.
他不是个流浪者
He's got his own house somewhere, not an apartment.
他有自己的独立房子而不是公寓
Why?
为什么？
What he does with them takes privacy.
他下毒手时，需要私人地方
He's in his 30s or 40s.
他年约三、四十岁
He's got real physical strength,
孔武有力……
combined with an older man's, uh, self-control.
还有中年人的自制能力
He's cautious, precise.
谨慎而精确
And he's never impulsive. He'll never stop.
他从来不冲动，也不会罢休
Why not?
为什么不？
He's got a real taste for it now.
他已经迷上了这回事
He's getting better at his work.
而且越来越熟练
Not bad, Starling.
不错，斯达琳
Questions?
有问题吗？
Yes, sir.
有的
You haven't mentioned anything...
你没有提及……
about the information contained in my report...
我报告里的任何资料……
or Dr. Lecter's offer, sir.
或者莱克特医生的提议
I'm considering it.
我正在考虑中
That's why you sent me in there, isn't it?
所以你派我去病院？
To get his help on Buffalo Bill, sir?
找他协助缉捕水牛比尔？
Well, if that was the case, then I just...
如果那是事实……
I just wish I was in on it. That's all.
我希望可以早点知道罢了
If I had sent you in there with an actual agenda,
如果以真正目的派你去……
Lecter would have known it instantly.
莱克特会立刻识破的
He would have toyed with you, then turned to stone.
他会玩弄你，什么也不会说
(格瑞格殡仪馆)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Excuse me. Sheriff Perkins, these are the FBI people.
打扰了，珀金斯警长，这些是联邦调查局人员
Sheriff Perkins. Jack Crawford, FBI.
珀金斯警长，我是联邦调查局的杰克·克劳福德
Special Agent Terry, Agent Starling.
这是泰瑞特别探员和斯达琳探员
We appreciate being invited to your jurisdiction.
感谢邀请我们来到你们的管辖区
I didn't call you. That was somebody from the State Attorney's office.
我没有邀请你们，是州政府检察官办公室的某人找你们的
We'll extend you every courtesy, but right now...
我们会全力合作，但现在……
Sheriff, this type of sex crime has certain aspects.
警长，这类性罪行有一些特定的细节
I'd just as soon discuss in private.
我认为该在私底下谈论
You know what I mean?
你明白吧？
(ORGAN PLAYING)
- PERKINS: Oscar, fetch Dr. Akin from the chapel.
- Yes, sir.
- 奥斯卡，去教堂叫区医生来
- 是的，长官
斯达琳，回这边来
Starling, we're back here.
Tell Lamar to come on when he's finished playing his music.
告诉拉玛弹完了风琴之后过来
Yeah. We'll be sending in a minute.
是的，我们稍后会传过来
Is this working?
行了？
I need a six-way linkup.
我需要搭建六线联系
Chicago, Detroit...
芝加哥、底特律……
What? What?
什么？什么？
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Excuse me! Excuse me, gentlemen.
对不起！对不起，先生们
You officers and gentlemen, listen here now.
各位警官先生，听我说
There's things we need to do for her.
我们要替她做一些事情
I know that you all brought her this far...
我知道你们把她大老远带来了这里……
and that her folks would thank you if they could...
她的家人会感谢……
for your kindness and your sensitivity.
你们的善意和体谅
And now, please, go on now and let us take care of her.
现在请离开吧，让我们照顾她好了
Go on, now.
走吧
Thank you.
谢谢你们
(OFFICER CHATTERING ON POLICE RADIO)
Thank you.
谢谢
CRAWFORD: Okay, good.
很好
Yeah, that's right. West Virginia. Elk River.
是的，西弗吉尼亚埃尔克河
Stand by for transmission.
准备传送
(BEEPING)
Ray.
瑞
CRAWFORD: Doctor, Lamar, let's take a look at her.
医生，拉玛，咱们来看看她吧
Oh, Jesus.
天啊
Okay, Starling.
斯达琳，行了
Bill.
比尔
Star-shaped contact entrance wound over the, uh, sternum.
胸骨上有星形的伤口
Uh, muzzle stamp at the top.
上面有个枪口印记
DR. AKIN: Wrongful death.
死于非命
"Wrongful death."
“死于非命”
She'll have to go to the state pathologist at Claxton.
她要被送去克莱克斯顿的病理学家那里
Well, I better get back to that service.
我还是回那个丧礼去了
Lamar will help you.
拉玛会帮你们的
Lord Almighty.
老天爷
(CAMERA CLICKING)
CRAWFORD: What else do you see, Starling?
你还观察到什么，斯达琳？
Well, she's not local.
她不是当地人
Her ears are pierced three times, and there's, uh...
她穿了三个耳洞，还有……
Glitter nail polish. It looks like town to me.
闪亮的指甲油，看来是城市人
Two of her fingernails are broken off,
她有两只指甲断了……
and there's, uh, there's dirt or grit under them.
指甲下有泥土和沙粒
It looks like she's tried to ciaw her way through something.
她好像想爬过一些什么似的
Ray, get pictures of her teeth.
瑞，替她的牙齿拍照
We'll fax them through Missing Persons.
稍后传真到失踪人口组
RAY: Right.
好的
Let's do another.
再拍一张
She's got something in her throat.
她喉咙里有什么东西
When a body comes out of the water,
当尸体被捞出水面时……
lots of times there's, like, leaves and things in the mouth.
口里总会有些树叶之类的东西
What is that, some kind of seedpod?
那是什么？某种豆荚吗？
No, sir. That's a bug cocoon.
不，是一只虫茧
There's no way that could get way down in there like that.
它决不可能自己走进去的
Not unless somebody shoved it in there.
除非有人把它塞进去
She'll be easier to print when we turn her over.
我们把她翻过来会较易采指纹
Lamar, will you give me a hand with this?
拉玛，你能帮我一把吗？
LAMAR: Yes, sir, I will.
好的
Oh, Jack. What do you make of these?
哦，杰克，你看这些是什么？
Different configuration than the other victims.
跟其他死者的形状不同，拍几张大特写
Get close-ups.
拍些近照
Victim's skin removed...
这次的死者……
this time in two large diamond-shaped sections above the buttocks.
臀部以上有两块菱形的皮肤被剥去
Stellate exit wound level with the second or the third thoracic vertebrae...
伤口底部靠近第二或第三节脊骨……
approximately six inches from the right shoulder blade.
上端距离右肩胛骨大约六英寸
CRAWFORD: Starling?
斯达琳？
When I told that sheriff...
我对那个警长说……
we shouldn't talk in front of a woman,
我们不该在女人面前谈……
that really burned you, didn't it?
那令你很气恼吧？
It was just smoke, Starling.
那只是个烟幕，斯达琳
I had to get rid of him.
我要打发他走
It matters, Mr. Crawford.
那很重要，克劳福德先生
Cops look at you to see how to act.
警察们想看你怎样应付
It matters.
那很重要
Point taken.
你明白了
Ligature marks found around the wrists,
手腕周围有被捆绑的痕迹……
not around the ankles.
足踝就没有
This would indicate that the skinning was postmortem.
显示死后才剥皮的
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
RODEN: Time, Pilch. My move.
时间到了，轮到我
PILCHER: No fair. You lured him with produce.
不公平，你用食物引诱它
Tough noogies. Still my turn.
真无赖，还是轮到我
Nice and slow, baby.
宝贝，慢慢来
If the beetle moves one of your men, does that still count?
如果那只甲虫推动你的棋子，也算数吗？
Of course it counts. How do you play?
当然算数，你怎么玩的？
Agent Starling?
斯达琳探员？
RODEN: Where the heck did this come from?
这东西从哪里来的？
It's practically mush.
它粘糊糊的
It was found behind the soft palate of a murder victim.
在一个被杀死者身上找到的
The body was in the Elk River, West Virginia.
尸体在西弗吉尼亚的埃尔克河里
It's Buffalo Bill, isn't it?
是水牛比尔干的吗？
I'm afraid I can't tell you any more about that.
恐怕我不能透露
PILCHER: We heard about it on the radio.
我们在电台听到了
You mean this is like a clue from a real murder case? Cool!
这是一起真实谋杀案的线索？酷！
Just ignore him. He's not a Ph.D.
别管他，他又不是博士
A Sphingid. Ceratomia, maybe.
小角天蛾，可能是
Boy, he's a big sucker.
它是只大吸血鬼
Okay.
好吧
Let's check morphology.
咱们查看一下形态学
Uh-huh.
啊哈
What do you do when you're not detecting, Agent Starling?
斯达琳探员，你不查案时会做什么？
I try to be a student, Dr. Pilcher.
做个学生，皮尔切博士
You ever go out for cheeseburgers and beer?
你会外出吃奶酪汉堡和喝啤酒吗？
The amusing house wine?
那有趣的招牌酒？
Are you hitting on me, Doctor?
博士，你是不是对我有意？
Yes.
是的
RODEN: Got you.
找到了！
What do you got, Roden?
你找到了什么，罗登？
Agent Starling, meet Mr. Acherontia styx.
斯达琳探员，这个是阴间冥河
Weird.
真奇怪
Better known to his friends as the Death's Head Moth.
认识它的人多叫它做骷髅飞蛾
And where does it come from?
它从哪里来的？
That's what's strange.
这正是古怪之处
- They only live in Asia.
- Asia?
- 它们只活在亚洲
- 亚洲？
In this country, they'd have to be...
在这个国家，他们得用……
specially raised from imported eggs.
进口的虫卵来进行特殊繁殖
Somebody grew this guy, fed him honey and nightshade,
有人饲养这只东西，喂它吃蜜糖和茄类植物……
kept him warm.
给它保暖
Somebody loved him.
有人很爱它
(INSECTS BUZZING)
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
(CATHERINE MUMBLING)
CATHERINE: Where are you?
你在哪里？
Let me out of here!
放我出去！
(CATHERINE SCREAMING)
(HUMMING)
喂！
(BARKS)
Please don't leave!
救我！
Talk to me, please!
求你救我
Why won't you answer me? Please!
干嘛你不答我？求求你！
Good morning. I'm Donna Ferucchi.
各位早，我是多娜·费鲁奇
I'm Gene Cassel with sports.
我是报导体育的吉恩·卡塞尔
And I'm Tim Langhorn.
我是提姆·郎霍
Our top story for this morning.
今早的头条新闻如下
Catherine Martin,
凯瑟琳·马丁……
the 25-year-old daughter of Senator Ruth Martin,
鲁思·马丁参议员的25岁女儿……
listed first as a missing person,
一度被列为失踪人士……
is now believed to have been kidnapped...
相信她已经被称为……
by the serial killer known only as Buffalo Bill.
『水牛比尔』的连环杀手所绑架
Memphis police sources indicate...
孟斐斯市警方说……
that the missing girl's blouse...
该名失踪女孩的上衣……
has been identified, sliced up the back...
已被找到，这件上衣后部被割破……
in what has become a kind of grim,
剪开的地方呈齿牙状……
all-too-familiar calling card.
这正是『水牛比尔』的标志
Young Catherine Martin, as we've said,
年轻的凯瑟琳·马丁，众所周知……
is the only daughter of U.S. Senator Ruth Martin,
是田纳西州共和党参议员……
the Republican junior senator from Tennessee.
鲁思·马丁的独生女
And while her kidnapping is not, at this point,
虽然这起绑架案目前来看……
considered to be politically motivated,
不具有政治动机……
nevertheless, it has stirred the government to its highest levels.
但政府最高层仍然相当重视
Reached for a comment on the ski slopes of Stowe, Vermont,
正在佛蒙特州斯托滑雪的总统……
the president himself said to be,
接受访问时表示……
and I quote, "Intensely concerned."
他『极度关注』
Just moments ago, Senator Martin...
马丁参议员于较早前……
- taped this dramatic personal plea:
- Excuse me.
- 录了以下的呼吁……
- 借过
MARTIN: I'm speaking now to the person who is holding my daughter.
我现在对挟持小女的人说话
Catherine is very gentle and kind.
凯瑟琳是非常温柔和善良的
Talk to her, and you'll see.
你跟她谈谈就知道
You have the power. You are in charge.
你有力量，你有控制权
I know you can feel love and compassion.
我知道你能感受到爱和善心的
You have a wonderful chance to show the whole world...
你有一个向全世界展示的大好机会……
that you can be merciful as well as strong,
就是你是仁慈而强大的……
that you're big enough to treat Catherine...
你有能力善待凯瑟琳……
better than the world has treated you.
比这个世界待你更好
You have that power.
你有那种能力
Please.
求你了
My daughter is Catherine.
我的女儿是凯瑟琳
ARDELIA: Boy, that's smart.
天啊，真是聪明
Release her unharmed.
不加损害释放她
Jesus, that's really smart.
天啊，真的很聪明
MAN: She keeps repeating the name.
她不断重复那个名字
If he sees Catherine as a person and not just an object,
如果他视凯瑟琳为一个人而非物件……
it's harder to tear her up.
就难以下毒手
Please. Release my little girl.
求你放了我的女儿
What you're doing, Miss Starling,
斯达琳小姐，你来干什么？
is coming into my hospital to conduct an interview...
你第三次来我的医院进行访问……
and refusing to share information with me for the third time.
并仍然拒绝跟我分享任何信息
Sir, I told you,
先生，我说过了……
this is just a routine follow-up on the Raspail case.
这不过是拉斯佩尔案的例行后续调查
He is my patient. I have rights.
他是我的病人，我有知情权
I understand that, sir.
我明白，先生
Look, I am not just some turnkey, Miss Starling.
听着，斯达琳小姐，我不是个笨蛋
This is the number for the U.S. Attorney's office.
这是美国司法部长办公室的电话号码
Please, either you discuss this with him,
请你要么跟他谈……
or you let me do my job. Do you understand?
要么让我执行任务，明白吗？
CLARICE: If your profile helps us catch Buffalo Bill
如果你的分析能帮助我们抓到水牛比尔……
in time to save Catherine Martin,
及时救出凯瑟琳·马丁……
the senator promises you a transfer...
参议员答应把你转送到……
to the V.A. Hospital at Oneida Park, New York,
V.A.医院，它位于纽约奥尼达公园……
with a view of the woods nearby.
可以看到附近的园林景色
Maximum security still applies, of course.
当然仍是高度设防的
You'd have reasonable access to books.
你可以阅读书籍
Best of all, though.
最好的是……
One week of the year,
每年有一周……
you get to leave the hospital and go here.
你可以离开医院去这里
Plum Island.
普拉姆岛
Every day of that week you may walk on the beach,
在那里的一星期里，你都可以在沙滩漫步……
you may swim in the ocean for up to one hour,
也可以在海中畅泳一小时
under SWAT team surveillance, of course.
当然是受到特警的监视
And there you have it.
这些资料给你
A copy of the Buffalo Bill case file.
水牛比尔的档案副本
A copy of the senator's offer.
参议员提供的条件副本
This offer is non-negotiable and final.
这个建议是无谈判余地的
If Catherine Martin dies, you get nothing.
凯瑟琳·马丁死了你就一无所得
(THUDDING)
"Plum Island Animal Disease Research Center."
“普拉姆岛动物病症研究中心”
Sounds charming.
听来很不错
That's only part of the island.
这只是那个岛的一部分
There's a very, very nice beach.
那个岛有非常棒的海滩
Terns nest there. There's beautiful...
岛上有燕鸥巢，有漂亮的……
Terns? Hmm.
燕鸥？嗯
If I help you, Clarice, it will be "turns" with us, too.
如果我帮你，克拉丽丝，这也会是我们的转机
Quid pro quo.
对等交换
I tell you things, you tell me things.
我们互相交换资料吧
Not about this case, though. About yourself.
但不是关于这个案件，是关于你自己
Quid pro quo. Yes or no?
对等交换，行还是不行？
Yes or no, Clarice?
行还是不行？克拉丽丝？
Poor little Catherine is waiting.
可怜的小克拉丽丝在等着呢
Go, Doctor.
好吧，医生
What is your worst memory of childhood?
你最糟的童年记忆是什么？
The death of my father.
家父去世
Tell me about it. And don't lie, or I'll know.
告诉我，别说谎，不然我会知道的
He was a town marshal,
他是镇上的警长……
and one night he surprised two burglars...
有一晚他意外遇上两个……
coming out of the back of a drugstore.
从药房走出来的窃匪
They shot him.
他们向他开枪
Was he killed outright?
他当场死亡？
No. He was very strong.
不是，他很强壮
He lasted more than a month.
熬了一个多月
My mother died when I was very young,
我母亲在我年幼时去世
so my father had become the whole world to me,
所以我父亲就成了我的全部世界
and when he left me, I had nothing.
他去世后，我一无所有
I was ten years old.
我那时十岁
You're very frank, Clarice.
你非常坦率，克拉丽丝
I think it would be quite something to know you in private life.
我认为了解你的个人生活很有用处
Quid pro quo, Doctor.
对等交换，医生
So tell me about Miss West Virginia.
那么告诉我西弗吉尼亚州小姐的情况吧
Was she a large girl?
她是不是块头很大？
Yes.
是的
Big through the hips? Roomy?
大屁股？肉团团？
They all were.
死者们全都是
What else?
还有什么线索？
She had an object deliberately inserted into her throat.
她的喉咙被异物用心地塞住
Now, that hasn't been made public yet.
现在这个细节还没有正式公布
We don't know what it means.
我们还不知道这是什么意思
Was it a butterfly?
是一只蝴蝶吗？
Yes. A moth.
是的，一只飞蛾
Just like the one we found in Benjamin Raspail's head an hour ago.
一小时前，我们在本杰明·拉斯佩尔的头颅内也找到了
Why does he place them there, Doctor?
为什么他把它们放进去，医生？
The significance of the moth is change.
飞蛾的特点是转变
Caterpillar into chrysalis or pupa,
幼虫变成蝶蛹或者蛹……
and from thence into beauty.
再变成美丽的蝴蝶
Our Billy wants to change, too.
咱们的比尔也想转变
There's no correlation in literature...
变性癖和暴力之间……
between transsexualism and violence.
是没有严格意义上的关联的
Transsexuals are very passive...
变性癖者是很被动的……
Clever girl.
很聪明
You're so close to the way you're gonna catch him.
你已经很接近抓到他了
Do you realize that?
知道吗？
No. Tell me why.
不知道，为什么？
After your father's murder, you were orphaned.
你父亲被杀后你成了孤儿
What happened next?
后来怎么样了？
I don't imagine the answer is on those second-rate shoes, Clarice.
我相信答案并非在那双廉价鞋子上，克拉丽丝
I went to live with my mother's cousin and her husband in Montana.
我去了蒙大拿州，跟我母亲的表妹夫妇同住
They had a ranch.
他们有一个牧场
Was it a cattle ranch?
牧牛场？
Sheep and horses.
牧羊和马
How long did you live there?
你在那里住了多久？
Two months.
两个月
Why so briefly?
为什么这么短？
I ran away.
我跑掉了
Why, Clarice?
为什么？克拉丽丝
Did the rancher make you perform fellatio?
牧场主人有没有逼你口交？
Did he sodomize you?
他有没有鸡奸你？
No. He was a very decent man.
没有，他是个很正派的人
Quid pro quo, Doctor.
对等交换，医生
Billy is not a real transsexual.
比尔不是个真正的变性癖者
But he thinks he is. He tries to be.
但他以为自己是，他试图做到
He's tried to be a lot of things, I expect.
我相信他试图做很多事情
And you said that I was very close...
你说过我已经很接近……
to the way we would catch him.
抓到他了
What did you mean, Doctor?
你什么意思，医生？
There are three major centers for transsexual surgery.
有三间主要做变性手术的中心
Johns Hopkins, the University of Minnesota, and Columbus Medical Center.
约翰霍普金斯、明尼苏达州大学和哥伦布医疗中心
I wouldn't be surprised if Billy had applied for sex reassignment...
如果比尔曾经向它们或其中一家申请做变性手术……
at one or all of them and been rejected.
而遭到拒绝，我也不会感到惊讶
On what basis would they reject him?
他们根据什么来拒绝他？
LECTER: Look for severe childhood disturbances...
试图寻找同暴力有关的……
associated with violence.
童年创伤吧
Our Billy wasn't born a criminal, Clarice.
比尔并非天生是个罪犯，克拉丽丝
He was made one through years of systematic abuse.
他是多年来系统性的虐待导致的
Billy hates his own identity, you see,
比尔讨厌自己的身份……
and he thinks that makes him a transsexual.
他以为那是令他成为变性癖者的原因
But his pathology is a thousand times more savage...
但他的病征要更凶残……
and more terrifying.
和可怕千倍
It rubs the lotion on its skin.
它涂润肤液在身上
It does this whenever it's told.
它听到指示总会依着做
Mister, my family will pay cash.
先生，我的家人会付钱的
Whatever ransom you're asking for, they'll pay it.
无论你要多少赎金，他们都会付
It rubs the lotion on its skin,
它涂润肤液在身上……
or else it gets the hose again.
否则又要挨打了
Yes, she will, Precious. She will get the hose.
是的，她会的，珍宝，她会挨打的
(SOBBING) Okay, okay, okay.
好吧，好吧，好吧
Okay. I'm there.
我做吧
Okay.
好的
Mister, if you let me go,
先生，如果你放我走……
I won't... I won't press charges.
我不会……我不会起诉你
I promise.
我保证
See, my mom is a real important woman.
我妈是个重要人物
I guess you already know that.
相信你也知道吧
Now it places the lotion in the basket.
它把润肤液放在篮里
Please! Please! I want to go home.
求求你！求求你！我想回家
I want to go home, please! Please, I want to...
我想回家！求求你！放我吧
It places the lotion in the basket.
把润肤液放在篮里
I want to see my mommy! Please.
我想见我妈妈，求你放我吧
I want to see my mother again.
我想再见到我妈妈
I want to... I want to see my mommy.
我想……我想见我妈妈
Put the fucking lotion in the basket!
把那他妈的润肤液放在篮里！
(PRECIOUS BARKING)
(CATHERINE SCREAMING)
(SHOUTING)
You still think you're gonna walk...
你还以为可以在沙滩上……
on some beach and see the birdies?
漫步和看鸟儿吗？
(LAUGHING) No, I don't think so.
不，我不这样认为
I called Senator Ruth Martin.
我给凯瑟琳·马丁参议员打过电话
She never heard of any deal with you.
她没听过任何同你有关的协议
They scammed you, Hannibal.
他们骗你，汉尼拔
Stand outside...
出去……
and shut the door.
把门关上
Barney.
巴尼
There never was a deal with Senator Martin, but there is now.
从没有跟马丁参议员的协议，但现在有了
I designed it.
是我议定的
Of course, I worked in a few conditions for my own benefit as well.
当然，我也为自己的利益定下了一些条件
Identify Buffalo Bill by name...
说出水牛比尔的名字……
and if the girl is found in time,
如果那个女孩及时被发现……
Senator Martin will have you transferred...
马丁参议员会把你转送到……
to Brushy Mountain State Prison in Tennessee.
田纳西州的丛树山州立监狱
Answer me, Hannibal.
回答我，汉尼拔
You answer me now,
你现在回答我……
or by God, you'll never leave this cell.
否则，天啊，你休想离开这个牢房
Who is Buffalo Bill?
水牛比尔是谁？
His first name is Louis.
他的名字是路易斯
I'll tell the rest to the Senator herself, but only in Tennessee,
其余的我只会在田纳西州亲自对参议员说……
and I have a few conditions of my own.
并且我也有几个条件
Clean him up and get him ready to go.
替他梳洗一下，准备出发
DIRECTOR ON PHONE: Jack, Hannibal Lecter is being transferred to Memphis.
杰克，汉尼拔·莱克特正被转送往孟斐斯途中
Transferred?
转送？
Did you have a trainee make some sort of...
你是不是有个见习生……
phony offer to Lecter in the Senator's name?
冒参议员之名向莱克特提出一个虚假的建议？
Yeah. I rolled the dice. I had to.
是的，这是我的主意，我逼不得已
Well, she's mad as hell, Jack.
她气疯了，杰克
Paul Krendler's over here from Justice.
司法部的保罗·克伦德勒来了
She's asking him to take over in Memphis.
她要求他在孟斐斯接手
(SIRENS WAILING)
(孟斐斯市国际机场)
Welcome to Memphis, Dr. Lecter.
莱克特医生，欢迎来到孟斐斯
I'm Lieutenant Boyle.
我是波依尔警长
This is Sergeant Patrick.
这位是帕特里克警官
Now, we're gonna treat you as good as you treat us.
我们会像你待我们一样好的
You be a gentleman, you gonna get three hots and a cot.
你做个绅士，就会得到舒服的待遇
Sir. If you sign right here,
先生，请在这里签名……
we'll have us a legal transfer.
我们完成法律移交
Where is it?
在哪签？
Here, sir. Use mine.
这个，先生，用我的吧
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Senator Martin, Dr. Hannibal Lecter.
马丁参议员，汉尼拔·莱克特医生
Dr. Lecter,
莱克特医生……
I brought an affidavit guaranteeing your new rights.
我带了一份宣誓书保证你新的权利
You'll want to read it before I sign.
在我签署前你会想先看看
I won't waste your time or Catherine's time...
我不会为了小利益……
bargaining for petty privileges.
而耽误你或凯瑟琳的时间
Clarice Starling and that awful Jack Crawford...
克拉丽丝·斯达琳和杰克·克劳福德……
have wasted far too much time already.
已经浪费了太多时间
I only pray they haven't doomed the poor girl.
但愿他们没有害死那个可怜的女孩
Let me help you now and I will trust you when it is all over.
让我帮你吧，事成后我会信任你
You have my word. Paul?
我答应你，保罗
Buffalo Bill's real name is Louis Friend.
水牛比尔的真名是路易斯·弗伦德
I met him just once.
我只见过他一次
He was referred to me in April or May, 1980,
1980年4、5月间由我的病人……
by my patient Benjamin Raspail.
本杰明·拉斯佩尔转介给我的
They were lovers, you see.
他们是爱人
But Raspail had become very frightened.
但拉斯佩尔变得很害怕
Apparently, Louis had murdered a transient...
显然，路易斯谋杀了一个过往旅客……
and done things with her skin.
并用他的皮肤做了一些东西
We need his address and a physical description.
我们要他的地址和容貌特征
Tell me, Senator.
告诉我，参议员……
Did you nurse Catherine yourself?
你有没有亲自哺育凯瑟琳？
What?
什么？
Did you breast-feed her?
你有没有给她喂奶？
Now, wait a minute!
等一下！
Yes, I did.
是的，我是的
Toughened your nipples, didn't it?
令你的乳头变得坚挺，是吗？
You son of a bitch!
你这个狗娘养的！
Amputate a man's leg, and he can still feel it tickling.
一个人的腿被切除了，他还能感到痒
Tell me, Mom, when your little girl is on the slab,
告诉我，妈妈，当你的小女儿被杀时……
where will it tickle you?
你哪里会感到痒？
Take this thing back to Baltimore.
把这个畜生带回巴尔的摩
Five-foot-ten, strongly built, about 180 pounds.
五英尺十英寸，身材魁悟，约一百八十磅
Hair, blond. Eyes, pale blue.
金发、浅蓝色眼睛
He'd be about 35 now.
他现在大约三十五岁
He said he lived in Philadelphia, but may have lied.
他声称住在费城，但可能是说谎
That's all I can remember, Mom.
我只记得这么多了，妈
But if I think of any more, I will let you know.
如果我再想起什么，我会通知你的
Oh, and, Senator, just one more thing.
哦，还有，参议员，还有一件事
Love your suit.
你的套装很漂亮
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
CHILTON: I tell you now that in a meeting earlier this evening...
我现在告诉你，在今晚较早前……
with Senator Ruth Martin,
与鲁思·马丁参议员会面时……
Dr. Lecter agreed to assist in the investigation...
莱克特医生同意协助调查……
of trying to find the abductor...
帮助追拿凯瑟琳·马丁的……
(谢尔比县法院大楼)
of Catherine Martin, Buffalo Bill.
绑架者，水牛比尔
How do you fit in, sir?
你是怎么促成的，先生？
Well, it's only through my own unique insight...
通过我对莱克特医生思想的……
into Lecter's mind that this breakthrough was possible.
独特视角，这次突破才成为可能
And Buffalo Bill's real name...
水牛比尔叫什么名字？
Buffalo Bill's real name is now a matter of record...
水牛比尔的名字是目前有关……
with the proper authorities.
当局的秘密
- Can you give us any more information?
- My name is Dr. Frederick Chilton.
- 能不能再多给我们些信息？
- 我是弗德里克·奇尔顿医生
- How do you spell that?
- C-H...
- 怎么拼的？
- 奇特的奇……
Are you with Dr. Chilton's group?
你是和奇尔顿医生一起的吗？
Oh, well, I just saw him outside, sir.
我刚在外面见到他
Access to Lecter is strictly limited.
接近莱克特是受到严格限制的
We've been getting death threats.
我们接到死亡恐吓
I understand, sir.
我明白的
Log in. Check your weapon.
登记和把武器放下
KRENDLER: Well, I can't take all the credit for myself.
我不能把功劳归到我一人身上
Senator Martin, the Justice Department, the people at the FBI,
马丁参议员、司法部和联邦调查局的……
the folks at the Baltimore State Hospital.
巴尔的摩州立医院的人员
And now for the hard part, apprehending the suspect.
最困难就是逮捕那个疑匪
Excuse me, folks, I'm gonna have to catch a flight.
对不起，我要赶飞机了
(PHONE RINGING)
Command desk. Officer Jacobs.
指挥台，我是杰科布斯警察
(路易斯·弗伦德飞禽、猥亵)
(铁)
OFFICER: Is it true what they're saying?
他们说的是事实吗？
Huh?
什么？
He's some kind of vampire?
他是个吸血殭尸？
They don't have a name for what he is.
他们没有替他取名
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
You do know the rules, ma'am?
小姐，你知道规矩的吧？
Yes, Lieutenant Boyle. I've questioned him before.
知道，我以前问过他问题
Go ahead.
去吧
Good evening, Clarice.
克拉丽丝，晚安
I thought you might like your drawings back, Doctor.
我想你可能想要回你的画吧
Just until you get your view.
直到你有自己的景观
How very thoughtful.
真是周到
Or did Jack Crawford send you for one last wheedle
还是在你们破案前，杰克·克劳福德派你来……
before you're both booted off the case?
说最后一次的花言巧语？
No. I came because I wanted to.
不，是我自己想来的
People will say we're in love.
人家会说我们在恋爱呢
(CLICKING TONGUE)
Anthrax Island.
安斯拉克斯岛
That was an especially nice touch, Clarice.
确实很动人，克拉丽丝
Yours?
你想的？
Yes.
是的
Yeah! That was good.
对！很好
Pity about poor Catherine, though.
但我同情可怜的凯瑟琳
Tick-tock, tick-tock, tick-tock, tick-tock.
滴答，滴答，滴答，滴答
Your anagrams are showing, Doctor.
你的字谜有破绽了
Louis Friend?
路易斯·弗伦德？
Iron sulfide, also known as Fool's Gold.
是硫化铁，也叫做黄铜铁
Oh, Clarice.
克拉丽丝
Your problem is you need to get more fun out of life.
你的毛病是，你要活得轻松一点
You were telling me the truth back in Baltimore, sir.
你在巴尔的摩时说了真话，先生
Please continue now.
现在继续吧
Well, I have read the case files, have you?
我看过那些档案了，你看过吗？
Everything you need to find him...
你要缉拿他的资料……
is right there in those pages.
都在里面
Then tell me how.
那么教我怎样做
First principles, Clarice. Simplicity.
首要的原则，克拉丽丝，是简易
Read Marcus Aurelius.
读读马可·奥勒留的《沉思录》吧
Of each particular thing, ask what is it in itself?
凡事都问：它的内在是什么？
What is its nature?
它的本质是什么？
What does he do, this man you seek?
你寻找的这个人，他做什么？
He kills women.
杀害女人
No! That is incidental.
不！那是附带发生的
What is the first and principal thing he does?
他第一和首要的是做什么？
What needs does he serve by killing?
他杀人是为了满足什么？
Anger.
愤怒
Um, social acceptance...
嗯，社会认同……
and, uh, sexual frustrations...
还有……呃……和性困惑……
No! He covets.
不是！他贪婪
That is his nature.
那是他的本性
And how do we begin to covet, Clarice?
我们怎样才会开始贪婪，克拉丽丝？
Do we seek out things to covet?
我们是否去寻找贪婪的东西？
Make an effort to answer now.
尝试回答吧
No. We just...
不是，我们只是……
No. We begin by coveting what we see every day.
我们看见日常的东西就开始贪婪
Don't you feel eyes moving over your body, Clarice?
你有没有感到一些眼睛在盯着你，克拉丽丝？
And don't your eyes seek out the things you want?
你的眼睛，又可有寻找你要的东西？
All right. Yes. Now please tell me how.
有的，请你告诉我吧
No. It is your turn to tell me, Clarice.
不，轮到你告诉我了，克拉丽丝
You don't have any more vacations to sell.
你再没有假期可哄骗我了
Why did you leave that ranch?
为什么你离开那个牧场？
Doctor, we don't have any more time for any of this now.
我们没有时间再玩这一套了
But we don't reckon time the same way, do we, Clarice?
但我们的时间观念是不同的，不是吗，克拉丽丝？
This is all the time you'll ever have.
你只有这么多的时间
Later. Now, please, listen to me. We've only got five...
稍后吧，请听着，我们只有五个……
No! I will listen now.
不！我现在就要听！
After your father's murder, you were orphaned.
父亲被杀后，你就成了孤儿
You were ten years old.
你当时才十岁
You went to live with cousins on a sheep and horse ranch in Montana.
你去了蒙大拿，跟一些养羊马的表亲同住
And?
之后呢？
And one morning, I just ran away.
我在一个早上跑掉了
Not "just", Clarice. What set you off?
不是的，什么驱使你离开？
You started at what time?
你在什么时候出发？
Early. Still dark.
很早，天还没亮
Then something woke you, didn't it?
有东西吵醒你，是吧？
Was it a dream? What was it?
是不是一个梦？是什么？
I heard a strange noise.
我听到一种奇怪的声音
What was it?
是什么？
It was screaming.
是尖叫声
Some kind of screaming, like a child's voice.
像小孩的尖叫声
What did you do?
你怎么做？
I went downstairs, outside.
我下楼，走出屋外
I crept up into the barn.
我偷进了壳仓
I was so scared to look inside, but I had to.
我很害怕看进去，但又必须看
And what did you see, Clarice?
你看见了什么？克拉丽丝？
What did you see?
你看见了什么？
Lambs. They were screaming.
一些羔羊，它们在尖叫
They were slaughtering the spring lambs?
他们在宰杀那些羔羊？
And they were screaming.
而它们在尖叫
And you ran away?
那你就跑掉了？
No.
不是
First I tried to free them. I...
最初我想释放它们。我……
I opened the gate to their pen, but they wouldn't run.
我打开它们的闸门，但它们不跑
They just stood there, confused.
它们只是站在那里，很困惑的
They wouldn't run.
不肯走
But you could and you did, didn't you?
但你可以走，你也走了，是不是？
Yes. I took one lamb, and I ran away as fast as I could.
是的，我抱起一只羊就拔足逃跑
Where were you going, Clarice?
你当时要去哪里，克拉丽丝？
I don't know.
我不知道
I didn't have any food, any water,
我没有食物和水……
and it was very cold, very cold.
而且当时很冷，非常冷
I thought...
我以为……
I thought if I could save just one, but,
我以为，至少可救下一只羊
he was so heavy.
但它很重
He was so heavy.
真的很重
I didn't get more than a few miles...
我走不了几哩路……
when the sheriff's car picked me up.
警长的车就把我截住
The rancher was so angry,
牧场主人很生气……
he sent me to live at the Lutheran orphanage in Bozeman.
把我送到博兹曼的路德会孤儿院
I never saw the ranch again.
我再没看过那个牧场了
What became of your lamb, Clarice?
你的羊又怎么样？
They killed him.
他们把它杀了
You still wake up sometimes, don't you?
有时你仍会惊醒，是吗？
Wake up in the dark and hear the screaming of the lambs?
在黑暗中醒来，听到那些羔羊的尖叫声？
Yes.
是的
And you think if you save poor Catherine,
你相信如果把凯瑟琳救了出来……
you could make them stop, don't you?
可以令它们停止尖叫，是吗？
You think if Catherine lives,
你相信如果凯瑟琳活着……
you won't wake up in the dark ever again...
你就不会在黑夜中……
to that awful screaming of the lambs.
再被那些可怕的羊叫声惊醒了
I don't know. I don't know.
我不知道，我不知道
Thank you, Clarice. Thank you.
谢谢你，克拉丽丝，谢谢你
Tell me his name, Doctor.
告诉我他的名字
Dr. Chilton, I presume.
是奇尔顿医生吧
I think you know each other.
我相信你们是认识的
Okay.
好吧
We found her.
我们找到他了
Let's go!
我们走吧！
It's your turn, Doctor.
医生，轮到你了
Out.
出去
Tell me his name.
说出他的名字
Sorry, ma'am, I've got orders.
抱歉，我接到命令
I have to put you on a plane.
要把你送上飞机
Come on now.
走吧
Brave Clarice.
勇敢的克拉丽丝
You will let me know when those lambs stop screaming, won't you?
那些羔羊停止尖叫时，你会告诉我的，是吗？
Tell me his name, Doctor!
告诉我他的名字，医生！
Clarice!
克拉丽丝！
Your case file.
你的档案
Hey!
喂！
Goodbye, Clarice.
再见，克拉丽丝
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(CLASSICAL PIANO MUSIC PLAYING ON RECORDER)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Ready when you are, Doc.
医生，准备好就来吧
Just another minute, please.
请等一会
The son of a bitch demanded a second dinner.
那个混蛋竟然还要再吃一顿晚饭
Lamb chops, extra rare.
还要极生的羊排
Wonder what he wants for breakfast.
不知道他早餐要吃什么
Some damn thing from the zoo?
动物园里的怪物？
(PEMBRY CHUCKLING)
(化学喷雾)
Good evening, gentlemen.
两位，晚安
Okay, Doc. Grab some floor.
好的，医生，蹲下吧
Same drill as before, please.
跟以前的程序一样
Mmm-hmm.
Ready when you are, Sergeant Pembry.
彭布瑞探员，准备好了
PEMBRY: Okay.
行了
BOYLE: Hand me that, would you?
递给我吧
Thanks.
谢谢
LECTER: Mind the drawings, please.
请小心那些画
Thank you.
谢谢你
Jimmy, watch it! He's got me!
彭布瑞，小心！他把我扣住了！
(SCREAMING)
Jesus Christ!
天啊
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
(PIANO MUSIC RESUMES)
(PEMBRY GRUNTING)
Ready when you are, Sergeant Pembry.
彭布瑞探员，准备好就来吧
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
TATE: What is this shit?
究竟什么回事？
Did somebody go up on five?
有人上了五楼？
No. Nobody went up.
不，没有人上去过
Call Pembry. Ask him...
叫彭布瑞，问他……
(GUN FIRING)
CP, shots fired on five. Repeat.
指挥部，五楼有枪声，重复
Shots fired on five.
五楼有枪声
Sergeant Tate.
泰特警官
(OFFICER CHATTERING ON RADIO)
去，五楼有枪声
TATE: Holy shit.
天啊！
- What the hell?
- Bitch!
- 怎么了？
- 混蛋！
Shut up.
闭嘴！
Bobby, get the vest.
鲍比，拿防弹衣来
Right, Sarge.
是，警官
TATE: Brady, Howard, cover...
布拉迪、霍华德，掩护……
Look!
看！
It stopped.
它停了
Seal off a 10 block radius.
封锁方圆十幢楼的范围
Get me the SWAT team and an ambulance double-quick.
召特警队和救护车来，快点！
We're going up.
我们上楼去
(OFFICER CHATTERING ON RADIO)
TATE: Pembry?!
彭布瑞？！
Boyle?!
波依尔？！
Oh, God!
天啊！
Go.
去
- Clear!
- OFFICER: Clear!
- 没有人
Command post, two officers down.
指挥站，两个警察死了
OFFICER 1 : Clear!
没有人！
OFFICER 2: Clear!
Lecter's gone, Sarge.
警官，莱克特不见了
The prisoner is missing.
囚犯失踪了
Boyle's gun is gone, Sergeant.
波依尔的配枪不见了
Repeat. Lecter is missing and armed.
重复，莱克特持械失踪了
He stripped the bed.
他拿走了床铺
Might be making a rope.
可能用来做绳
Check all windows.
搜查所有窗户
Where the fuck is my ambulance?
该死的救护车在哪里？
He's alive.
他还活着
Sergeant Tate, he's alive!
泰特警官，他仍活着！
Get ahold of him where you can feel his hands, son.
扶着他，抚摸他的手，孩子
Talk to him.
跟他说话
What do I say?
说什么？
It's Jim Pembry! Now talk to him, damn it!
他是吉姆·彭布瑞！跟他说话，该死！
Lecter is missing and armed.
莱克特持械失踪了
Pembry. Pembry, can you hear me?
彭布瑞……你听得到我吗？
He took Boyle's gun.
他拿走了波依尔的配枪
Pembry got off one round.
彭布瑞开过一枪
There's a chance Lecter was hit.
莱克特可能中了枪的
Keep breathing in and out. That's it.
继续呼吸吧，就这样
You're doing a good job.
你做得很好
You look real good there.
你看上去很好
Yeah, you look... You look real good.
对，你看上去……你看上去真的很好
(SIRENS WAILING)
- You ready?
- Let's go!
- 你准备好了吗？
- 咱们上！
Let's do it.
咱们行动吧
Let's go.
咱们上
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Looking good, Pembry. You're gonna make it.
很好，彭布瑞，你支持得住的
You're just fine. You're doing all right. That's right.
你没事的，你很好
Okay, I need that IV now.
我要作静脉注射
Lactated ringers.
乳酸盐液
Can we get the strap?
我们能不能拿那条带子来？
Where's the fucking oxygen?
见鬼的氧气在哪里？
- Looking good, buddy. That's right.
- TATE: Bob!
- 老兄，情况很好，很好
- 鲍勃！
Stay with me. Stay with me here.
留下来陪我，留下来陪我
We're losing him. Downstairs. Take him!
他不行了，去楼下，快点！
And up!
抬起！
Elevator! Out of the way!
电梯！让开！
Out of the way!
让开！
OFFICER ON RADIO: CP to Tate.
指挥部呼叫泰特
Roger, Lieutenant. Tate here.
收到，我是泰特
(BEEPING)
I'm on the elevator bringing Pembry down.
我现在乘电梯送彭布瑞下来
He seems to be hanging on.
他看来支持得住
Top three floors secured.
最高的三层楼封锁了
Main stairwell secured.
主要楼梯封锁了
We think he's on two.
我们相信他在二楼
Tate, are you still with me?
泰特，你还能听到吗？
We're pretty sure he's somewhere on two, sir.
我们相当肯定他在二楼，长官
That's all for now. Over.
这是目前全部情况。完毕
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
He's on the roof of the elevator.
他在电梯顶
Okay, guys.
好的，大家来
I see him.
我看到他了
There's a gun by his hand. He's not moving.
他的手边有一支枪，他没有动
One warning. We need him alive.
警告，我们要生擒他
JOHNNY: Got him.
知道
Lecter?
莱克特？
Put your hands on your head.
把双手放在头上
One in the leg.
向腿射一枪
(GUN CLICKING)
No movement.
没有动静
Johnny, hold your fire. We're coming into the car.
约翰，不要开枪，我们要进入电梯
We're opening the hatch.
我们会打开盖口
Watch his hands.
小心他的手
If there's any fire, it'll come from us. Affirm.
如果有开火，会是我们开的，确定
JOHNNY: Got it.
明白
(SIREN WAILING)
Memphis General, this is Medical Unit 26.
孟斐斯医院，这是26号车
We're inbound with a 50-year-old male police officer...
我们会送来一名五十岁男性警官……
with severe facial lacerations. Weapon unknown.
他面部有严重割伤，伤害武器不明
We've got grand mal seizure activity, but he's postictal now.
他全身出现抽搐，情况严重
WOMAN: Copy that.
收到
Vital signs are good.
重要器官情况良好
Pressure is 1 30 over 90.
血压是130/90
- 90?
- Yeah, that's right. 90.
- 血压90？
- 对，是90，
Pulse, 84.
脉搏84
We've got him on lactated ringers running.
我们给他注射了乳酸盐液
And the patient is on 1 0 liters...
病人正在吸十公升的氧气
小心！
ARDELIA: They found the ambulance...
他们在孟斐斯机场……
in a parking garage at Memphis Airport.
一个车库里发现了那辆救护车
The crew was dead.
工作人员死了
He killed a tourist, too.
他还杀了一名游客
Got his clothes, cash.
拿了他的衣服和钞票
By now he could be anywhere.
他现在可能在任何地方
He won't come after me.
他不会来对付我的
Oh, really?
哦，真的？
No, he won't. I can't explain it.
不，他不会的，我无法解释
He... He would consider that rude.
他……认为那样做很无礼
It's over. She's dead.
都完了，她死定了
It's not your fault it worked out like this.
事情演变至此不是你的错
The thing is that, Lecter said everything we need to catch him with...
问题是，莱克特说我们需要捉拿他的资料……
is right here in these pages, only I can't...
都在这里，只是我无法……
Dr. Lecter said a lot of things.
莱克特医生说了很多事
He's here, Ardelia.
阿德利亚，他在这里的
(SNIFFING)
Is this Lecter's handwriting?
这是莱克特的笔迹吗？
"Clarice, doesn't this random scattering of sites...
“克拉丽丝，这样杂乱地分布现场……
"seem desperately random?
“看上去不是有点极度随意吗？
"Like the elaboration of a bad liar.
“像个差劲的说谎者的精心策划
"Ta, Hannibal Lecter."
“汉尼拔·莱克特”
Desperately random? What does he mean?
『极度随意』？他是什么意思？
Not random at all maybe.
可能根本不是随意
Like there's some pattern here.
是有一个模式的
Yeah, but there is no pattern,
对，但并没有模式……
or the computers would have nailed it.
否则电脑也会发现的
They're even found in random order.
尸体甚至是不依次序被发现的
Random because of the one girl.
不依次序是因为那个女孩
The one he weighted down.
那个被他沉下的女孩
- Fredrica Bimmel...
- Right.
- 弗瑞德瑞卡·比默……
- 对
From Belvedere, Ohio.
来自俄亥俄州的贝尔维迪尔
First girl taken, third body found. Why?
第一个遇害的女孩，尸体是第三个被发现，为什么？
Well, she didn't drift. He weighted her down.
她没有漂浮，他把她沉下去
What did Lecter say about the first principles?
莱克特说的首要原则是什么？
Simplicity.
简易
What does this guy do? He covets.
这个家伙做什么？他贪婪
How do we first start to covet?
我们怎样开始贪婪的？
We covet what we see...
我们贪婪见到的东西……
Every day.
每天见到的
Hot damn, Clarice.
该死，克拉丽丝
He knew her.
他认识她的
(俄亥俄州贝尔维迪尔市)
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(SQUEAKING)
Mr. Bimmel?
比默尔先生？
That's me.
我是
Hello. I'm Clarice Starling. I'm with the FBI.
你好，我是克拉丽丝·斯达琳，联邦调查局探员
CLARICE: I sure appreciate you letting me...
比默尔先生，如果你能让我……
take a look around, Mr. Bimmel.
四周看看，我会很感激你的
I don't know nothing new to tell you.
我没有什么新资料给你了
Police been back here so many times already.
警方已经来过很多次
Fredrica went into Chicago on the bus to see about a job.
弗瑞德瑞卡坐巴士去芝加哥求职
She left the interview okay.
她好端端地离开面试
She never come home.
再也没有回家
Her bedroom's how she left it.
她的卧房是原封不动的
Upstairs. Door to the left.
在楼上，左边那一间
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING)
(CAT MEOWING)
CLARICE: He's making himself a woman suit, Mr. Crawford,
他在替自己做女装，克劳福德先生……
out of real women.
用真的女人做
And he can sew, this guy. He's very skilled.
他还懂得缝纫，他很熟练
He's a tailor or a dressmaker or...
他是个裁缝或……
CRAWFORD: Starling!
斯达琳！
That's why they're all so big. He has to keep them alive...
所以她们都身材肥大，他让她们活着……
so he can starve them a while,
逼使她们挨饿……
so he can loosen their skin and take...
令她们的皮肤松弛，然后……
Starling.
斯达琳
Starling! Starling, we know who he is and where he is!
斯达琳！斯达琳，我们知道了他的身份和下落！
We're on our way right now.
我们快到达了
CLARICE: Where?
哪里？
Calumet City, edge of Chicago.
芝加哥卡柳梅特城
Be on the ground in 45 minutes with HRT.
我45分钟后会和特警队降落
Oh, that's great news, sir, but how...
哦，这是好消息，长官，但怎么……
Johns Hopkins came up with some names.
约翰霍普金斯提供了一些名字
We fed him into "Known Offenders."
我们输入已知犯人的档案
Subject's name is Jamie Gumb, AKA John Grant.
他叫杰米·冈姆布，又名约翰·格兰特
Lecter's description is accurate. He just lied about the name.
莱克特的描述是正确的，他只是捏造了那个名字
Listen to this. Customs had some paper on him.
听我说，海关有些关于他的资料
They stopped a carton two years ago at LAX.
两年前他们在洛杉矶机场查到一个纸箱
Live caterpillars from Surinam.
是一些来自苏里南的活毛虫
The addressee was a Jame Gumb.
收件人叫詹姆·冈姆布
Well, Chicago's only 400 miles from here.
芝加哥离这里只有四百哩
I'll be there in...
我很快就到那里……
No, no, no, Starling.
不，不，不，斯达琳
There's not enough time.
没有时间了
We want him for murder, not kidnapping.
我们要控告他谋杀，不是绑架
I need you to link him to the Bimmel girl before he's indicted.
在起诉他前，要找出他与弗瑞德瑞卡·比默的关系
See what you can dredge up in Belvedere.
你去贝尔维迪尔看有什么发现
Yes, sir. You bet. I'll do my best.
是的，长官，我会尽力的
Starling, we wouldn't have found him without you.
斯达琳，没有你我们就找不到他，
Nobody's gonna forget that. Least of all me.
大家都会记着这点，尤其是我
Thank you, sir.
谢谢，长官
Thank you very much, Mr. Crawford.
谢谢你，克劳福德先生
Mr. Crawford?
克劳福德先生？
CATHERINE: Thanks for the scraps, asshole.
混蛋，谢谢那些冷饭菜汁
I got a better idea.
我有更好的主意
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GOODBYE HORSES PLAYING ON RECORDER)
Okay, Precious. Time for a little treat.
好吧，珍宝，我来招呼你吧
(GROWLING)
Precious!
珍宝！
(WHISTLING)
Come on, girl!
乖乖，来吧！
Come on, Precious. Come on, Precious!
来吧，珍宝，乖，珍宝！
∮ I see you rise ∮
∮ But it always falls ∮
Come on, Precious!
来吧，珍宝！
I got a yummy, yummy snack for you.
我有好吃的点心给你
Come on. Come and get it.
来吧，来吃吧
∮ He said ∮
∮ All things pass into the night ∮
Precious!
珍宝！
Are you up there, you little shit?
小畜牲，你在上面吗？
Come and get it, pretty girl.
来得到它，可爱的姑娘
∮ I must disagree ∮
∮ Oh, no, sir ∮
∮ I must say ∮
Precious. Please come. Come on.
珍宝，求你来吧，来吧
∮ You told me ∮
∮ I've seen it all before ∮
(CRYING) Come on...
来吧……
∮ I've seen my hopes and dreams ∮
∮ Are lying on the ground ∮
∮ I've seen the sky ∮
∮ Just begin to fall ∮
Would you fuck me?
你想操我吗？
CATHERINE: Come on. Take that bone. Come on.
来吃骨头吧
Come on. Come. Come on.
来吧，来吧，来吧
I'd fuck me.
我想操自己
Come on.
来吧
(YELPING)
I'd fuck me hard.
我想狠狠地操自己
I'd fuck me so hard.
No!
不！
∮ Goodbye horses ∮
∮ I'm flying over you ∮
(SINGING) ∮ I'm flying, flying, flying over you ∮
(伊利诺斯州芝加哥市，空军国民警卫队总部)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(莫克斯利药房)
Is that a good job, FBI agent?
当联邦密探很棒吧？
You get to travel around and stuff?
要经常出门的吗？
I mean, better places than this?
我是说，去比这里好的地方？
Sometimes you do.
有时要的
Freddie was so happy for me when I got this job at the bank.
我找到这份银行工作时，弗瑞德瑞卡很替我高兴
Toaster giveaways and Barry Manilow on the speakers all day.
有烤面包机赠品，还有整天播着巴瑞·曼尼罗的歌曲
She thought it was such hot shit.
她觉得这是份好差事
What did she know? Big dummy.
她知道什么？大笨蛋
Stacy, did Fredrica ever mention a man...
斯黛西，弗瑞德瑞卡有没有提过一个……
named Jamie Gumb or a Jame Gumb?
叫杰米·冈姆布的男人？或者詹姆·冈姆布的人？
How about John Grant?
约翰·格兰特呢？
No.
没有
Oh, would she have had a friend that you didn't know about, or...
她有没有一个你不认识的朋友，或……？
No way. If she had a guy, I'd have known, believe me.
不可能，如果她有男朋友，我一定会知道
Sewing was her life.
缝纫是她的命根
Did you two ever work together?
你们曾一起工作吗？
Oh, sure. Me and Pam Malavesi used...
哦，是的，我和潘·玛拉维西曾帮她……
to help her do alterations for old Mrs. Lippman.
一起做利普曼太太的替工
Can you give me Mrs. Lippman's address?
可以把她的地址给我吗？
I need to talk to her.
我要跟她谈谈
(伊利诺斯州卡柳梅特城)
(INSECTS BUZZING)
So powerful. So beautiful.
太有劲了，真的漂亮
(PRECIOUS YELPING)
Precious?
珍宝？
CATHERINE: Down here, you sack of shit!
这里，你为烂人！
Put her in that bucket.
把它放在桶里
No! You get me a telephone and lower it down here. Now!
不！你立刻给我吊个电话下来！
Poolie-poo. Precious.
乖乖，珍宝？
Darling heart, are you all right?
亲爱的宝贝，你没事吧？
She's in a lot of pain, mister.
她很痛苦
She needs a vet.
她需要找兽医
She broke her leg on the way down.
她下来时折断了腿
I know it. She's been licking...
我知道，她在舐……
Hey, don't you hurt my dog!
你敢伤害我的狗！
Don't you make me hurt your dog!
你别逼我伤害你的狗！
Oh, you don't know what pain is!
你不知道什么是痛楚！
Get me a live telephone line down here or the dog's dead!
给我拿电话来，否则我杀死它！
Damn fuck.
他妈的！
CATHERINE: Get me that telephone!
你还是给我拿电话来！
I'm gonna do it, mister!
我要动手了，先生！
I'll snap her neck off. I swear to God!
我会折断它的颈，我发誓我会的！
You little fuck.
你这小婊子
(RINGING)
CATHERINE: Down here! Down here!
下面！下面！
Help!
救命！
Okay, I'm coming.
好的，我来了
We're going in.
我们进去
Good afternoon. Sorry to bother you.
午安，抱歉打扰你
I'm... I'm looking for Mrs. Lippman's family.
我在……我在找利普曼太太的家人
FBI! Everybody down!
联邦调查局！所有人趴下！
Everybody down, now!
所有人趴下！马上！
No. The Lippmans don't live here anymore.
利普曼一家搬走了
No. Excuse me, sir.
对不起，先生
I really need to speak with you.
我真的需要跟你谈谈
- Clear!
- 没有人！
(STUTTERING) What's the problem, Officer?
有什么问题呢，警官？
Well, I'm investigating the death of Fredrica Bimmel.
我正在调查弗瑞德瑞卡·比默尔的死因
There's no one here, Jack.
这里一个人也没有，杰克
Clarice.
克拉丽丝
Your name is?
阁下是……
Oh, Jack Gordon.
杰克·戈登
Mr. Gordon. Good. Um...
戈登先生，很好，嗯……
Well, Fredrica used to work for Mrs. Lippman.
弗瑞德瑞卡是利普曼太太的雇员
Did you know her?
你认识她吗？
No. Uh-uh.
不认识
Oh, wait.
等一下
Was she a great, big fat person?
她是不是身材肥胖？
Yes. She was a big girl, sir.
是，她很肥胖
Yeah, I...
对，我……
I may have...
我可能有……
No, I read about her in the newspaper.
不，我是在报纸上读到她的新闻
Um...
嗯……
Mrs. Lippman had a son. Maybe he could help you.
利普曼太太有个儿子，他或许可以帮忙
I got his card in here someplace.
我这里有他的名片
Do you want to come in while I look for it?
在我找他名片的时候你要进来吗？
- May I?
- Yeah, sure.
- 可以吗？
- 当然可以
Thank you.
谢谢
Are you close to catching somebody, you think?
你觉得你们快抓到人了吗？
Yes. We may be.
是的，或者吧
Did you...
你是不是……
take over this place after Mrs. Lippman died? Is that right?
在利普曼太太死后搬到这里来？
Yeah. I bought this house, uh, two years ago.
是的，我两年前买了这间屋
Did she leave any records, any business records,
她有没有留下任何记录，任何业务记录……
tax forms, list of employees?
税单、雇员名单之类？
No. Nothing like that at all.
没有，完全没有
Say, has the FBI learned something?
联邦调查局有什么发现吗？
The police around here don't seem to have the first clue.
这里的警方看来毫无头绪
I mean, have you got, like, a description, fingerprints,
我是说，你们有没有获得相貌、指纹……
anything like that?
之类的线索？
No.
没有
No, we don't.
我们没有
Yeah. Here's that number.
对，是这个电话号码了
Very good, Mr. Gordon.
很好，戈登先生
May I use your phone, please?
可不可以借用你的电话？
Sure you can use my phone.
当然可以
Freeze!
别动！
Put your hands over your head!
把双手放在头上！
And turn around! Spread your legs!
转过来！张开腿！
Spread your legs!
张开腿！
Put your hands in the back! Thumbs up!
把双手放在……
Freeze!
别动！
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PRECIOUS BARKING)
CATHERINE: Hey!
喂！
(MUSIC PLAYING)
CATHERINE: Hello! Are you there?
喂！你在吗？
I'm down here! I'm down here!
我在下面！我在下面！
(PRECIOUS BARKING)
Catherine Martin?
凯瑟琳·马丁？
CATHERINE: Yes!
是！
FBI! You're safe!
联邦调查局！你安全了！
Safe, shit! Get me out of here!
安全个屁！快救我出去
(GRUNTS)
You're all right, Catherine. Where is he?
你没事的，凯瑟琳。他在哪里？
How the fuck should I know?
我他妈的怎么知道？
Just get me out of here!
快救我出去！
Catherine, you've got to be quiet. Now shut that dog up!
凯瑟琳，你静一点，叫那只狗别吵！
Just get me out of here!
快救我出去！
Oh, my God.
我的天
Catherine, I'm going to get you out of there,
凯瑟琳，我会救你出来的……
but right now, you listen to me.
但现在你要听我说
I've got to leave this room. I'll be right back.
我得离开这个房间，我会回来的
No! Don't you leave me here, you fucking bitch!
不！不要丢下我，你这个婊子！
No! Don't you leave me here!
不！不要丢下我！
This guy's fucking crazy!
这个家伙是疯子！
Wait!
等一下！
I've got to get out of here!
我得离开这里！
Please!
求求你！
Catherine, the other officers will be here any minute now!
凯瑟琳！其他的探员会很快到达的！
Wait!
不要走！
Don't go! Please!
不要走！求求你！
CLARICE: Quiet!
别吵！
Oh, God!
天啊……
(恐怖)
(比尔剥下第五个人的皮)
(OFFICER CHATTERING ON RADIO)
You okay?
你没事吧？
- Gunpowder. It's nothing. I'm okay.
- Agent Starling,
- 枪震，不要紧，我没事
- 斯达琳探员……
how did you track Buffalo Bill to this address?
你怎么追查到水牛比尔在这里的？
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
(司法部联邦调查局)
Clarice M. Starling.
克拉丽丝·M.斯达琳
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Ernest W. Stevens.
厄内斯特·W.斯蒂文斯
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Special Agent Starling!
特别探员克拉丽丝·斯达琳！
Oh, Special Agent Mapp.
哦，特别探员麦普
- Phone call.
- Thank you.
- 有电话找你
- 谢谢
Excuse me, gentlemen.
失陪，先生们
Starling.
斯达琳
Pilch, could you take our picture?
皮尔奇，能替我们拍张照吗？
Sure.
好的
Look, I just wanted to say congratulations.
我只想说声恭喜
And I'm not much good at this kind of thing,
我不擅应酬这类事……
so I'm gonna duck out of here.
所以我要走了
Okay, sure.
好的
Thank you, Mr. Crawford.
谢谢，克劳福德先生
Your father would have been proud today.
令尊今天一定会很骄傲
Don't forget your phone call.
别忘了接听电话
Starling.
斯达琳
Well, Clarice, have the lambs stopped screaming?
那么，克拉丽丝，那些羔羊停止尖叫了吗？
Dr. Lecter.
莱克特医生？
Don't bother with a trace. I won't be on long enough.
不必追踪这个电话，我不会说太久
Where are you, Dr. Lecter?
莱克特医生，你在哪里？
I have no plans to call on you, Clarice.
我不打算找你了
The world's more interesting with you in it.
有了你，这个世界更加有趣
So you take care now to extend me the same courtesy.
所以你多保重，日后报答我吧
You know I can't make that promise.
你知道我不能做那个承诺的
I do wish we could chat longer,
但愿我们可以多聊一会……
but I'm having an old friend for dinner.
但我有个老朋友要一起吃晚饭
Bye.
再见
Dr. Lecter!
莱克特医生！
Dr. Lecter.
莱克特医生
Dr. Lecter?
莱克特医生？
Hey, what? Oh, excuse me. I'm sorry.
嘿，什么？抱歉，对不起
Is the security system all set up?
保安系统安排好了吗？
We have the big-shot security.
我们有严密保安的
Thank you. I appreciate that.
谢谢，我很感谢
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(MAN SINGING)
(谨以本片献给崔·威尔森)